Guide to the George W. Van Metre papers, 1732-1943, bulk 1830-1910. RL.10052
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
George Van Metre papers
1732-1943, bulk 1830-1910
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Van Metre, George
RL.10052
9 Linear Feet
George Van Metre was a civil engineer, real estate dealer, local politician and local recorder of weather conditions at Martinsburg, West Virginia. The collection includes surveying notes, drawings, personal and business correspondence and papers of Van Metre as well as William Ferrel and members of his family. Also included are weather observations, account books and letters from a missionary in India.
Biographical note
George Van Metre was a civil engineer, real estate dealer, local politician and local recorder of weather conditions at Martinsburg, West Virginia.
Collection Overview
The collection is predominantly composed of surveying notes and drawings, together with personal and business correspondence and papers of Van Metre, of William Ferrel (1817-1891), meteorologist, and of other members of the Van Metre and Ferrel (Ferrell) families of West Virginia. The Van Metre and Ferrel families were connected through marriage. The collection also includes weather observations, business diaries, letters relating to family matters, medical records, letters from a missionary in India about her experiences and the people she encounters, and account books.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The George W. Van Metre paers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1954.
Meteorology -- Observations; Civil engineers -- Correspondence; Surveying -- Records; West Virginia -- Climate; Missions -- India; West Virginia -- Genealogy; Missionaries -- Correspondence; Meteorologists -- United States; Van Metre family; Ferrel family; Van Metre, George
- George W. Van Metre Papers, 1
  - Letters and Papers, 1732-1879; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Letters and Papers, 1880-1909; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Letters and Papers, 1910-1943 and undated; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Letters, Papers and Pictures, undated; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1874-1900; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1901-1904; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1905-1908; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1909-1918 and undated; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Daybook, 1853-1879 (Volume F:6392)
  - Medical Notes, 1856-1857 (Volume M:5929)
  - Memorandum Book, 1864-1866 (Volume S:5930)
  - Account Book, 1884-1890 (Volume S:5891)
  - Diary, 1889 (Volume S:5892)
  - Diary, 1890 (Volume S:5893)
  - Diary, 1891 (Volume S:5894)
  - Surveyor's Notes, 1887-1901 (Volume M:5895)